vertical-leap.net 2011-11-16

# Our Privacy Policy | Vertical Leap - The Search Marketing Specialists

**Our Privacy Policy falls into two sections. 1) Privacy Statement for Customers Using Vertical Leap’s search engine marketing service 2) Privacy Statement for Visitors to Sites Tracked by Vertical Leap**

At Vertical Leap Ltd, providing our customers with useful Analytics without infringing on privacy is of the utmost importance. You may wish to review this entire document, or you can skip to the section that is most relevant to your area of interest.

**General Information**  
Vertical Leap is committed to maintaining the trust and confidence of its customers and visitors to our web sites. We are also committed to the security of the data we collect for sites using Search Analytics, and the trust and confidence of visitors who frequent those sites. That’s why we want you to understand when we collect and use information about you, the actions we take to protect your privacy and our commitment to data security. Because your privacy is important, Vertical Leap will not sell, rent or trade your personal information except as outlined in this privacy statement.

**What is Vertical Leap’s business?**  
Vertical Leap Ltd provides a fully managed search engine marketing service (including [search engine optimisation](http://www.vertical-leap.co.uk/seo/)) for its clients with the express aim of improving their website’s ranking positions in the main organic search engines such as Google and MSN.

The following documents describe our privacy practices for www.vertical-leap.co.uk. It details how we handle the information we gather about visitors to our customers’ web sites running Vertical Leap Search Analytics as well as information about our customers’ visits to www.vertical-leap.co.uk to retrieve their reports.

If you have visited a site that uses Vertical Leap’s Search Analytics, and desire more information about what anonymous information is collected, what we do and do not do with that information, and how to opt-out, click here:

Privacy Statement for Visitors to Sites Tracked by Vertical Leap Search Analytics

If you are a Vertical Leap customer, and you are interested in more information about our use of your personal account information, please click here:

Privacy Statement for Customers Using Vertical Leap’s search engine marketing service

Privacy Statement for Customers Using Vertical Leap Search Analytics to track visitors to their websites from organic search engines.

**Privacy Principles**  
Because your privacy is important to us, Vertical Leap conducts its business under the following privacy principles:

**Principle 1 – Your Information is Secure**  
All the statistical information we compile for your web site and personal information that we collect about you is considered confidential. This information is protected by usernames and passwords. You should keep your password and user name confidential. We have implemented industry standard security mechanisms to protect this information from loss, misuse and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Examples include limited access, firewalls and security analysers using SSL encryption to protect transmission of data. Vertical Leap Search Analytics are configured to provide effective security.

**Principle 2 – Vertical Leap Ltd Has Limited Access to your Information**

Vertical Leap Ltd will not access, modify, or otherwise divulge the statistical information we compile for your site except for the express purpose of generating reports which have been authorised by you or otherwise agreed to by you, or unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Vertical Leap Ltd; (3) enforce our agreements with customers and visitors; or (4) troubleshoot any service problems.

**Principle 3 – Use of Cookies, Off Site Java-Script and other Data Collection Methods**  
Cookies are small pieces of information that a web site transfers to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Java-Script

Either can make a web site more useful by allowing the site to personalise information for visitors and by storing information about customer preferences on a particular site. The use of both is an industry standard, and many major web sites use them to provide useful features for their customers.

For customers of Vertical Leap Live, we store the following information:

* Subscription status  
* User language  
* User ID

We use this information for the following purposes:

* To identify you  
* To customise our site for you  
* To help improve navigation

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to reject cookies. However, you will not be able to use Vertical Leap’s Apollo Campaign Management System if you do not accept the cookie defined above.

Your visitors can also reject cookies. If a visitor to your web site rejects cookies, Vertical Leap captures only a part of the information necessary to generate all traffic reports. .

**Principle 5 – Personal Information**  
Vertical Leap’s registration form requires users who sign up for the search engine marketing service to give us contact information (such as their name, telephone and e-mail address). At no point will this information be sold, rented or in any way released without your express permission.

**Principle 6 – Access to Personal Information Stored at Vertical Leap**  
Customers have access to personal information about them that Vertical Leap holds in the Apollo database through the web-based administrative console located at http://www.vertical-leap.co.uk/signin customers can correct this information where it is inaccurate. This is the only place that a customer must change their information to ensure full functionality of the Vertical Leap service.

**Principle 7 – Opting Out**  
Individuals may opt-out of receiving future marketing e-mailings from Vertical Leap. To remove your name from our e-mail list, please go to http://www.vertical-leap.co.uk/

**Principle 8 – Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
If Vertical Leap makes any material changes to the way we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by e-mail.

**For More Information**  
If you have any questions or comments about this policy, our services, or your experience with Vertical Leap Ltd, you can use the Feedback page on our site, or write to us at:

Vertical Leap Ltd  
Boathouse 6  
19 College Road  
Portsmouth Historic Dockyard  
Portsmouth, Hampshire  
PO1 3LJ  
England

**Privacy Statement for Visitors to Sites Tracked by Vertical Leap Ltd**

**Privacy Principles**  
Because your trust and confidence is important to us, Vertical Leap conducts its business under the following privacy principles:

**Principle 1 – No Collection of Personal Information**

Vertical Leap Ltd does not collect any personal information such as names, ages, phone numbers, addresses or e-mail addresses from visitors to our customer’s web sites.

**Principle 2 – No Combination of Browsing and Web Traffic Information with Personal Information**  
Since Vertical Leap Ltd does not collect any personal information from website visitors, we do not combine traffic analysis information with personal information such as name, age, phone number or postal address.

**Principle 3 – No Aggregation of Individual Visitor Traffic Patterns across Multiple Sites**  
Vertical Leap Ltd does not collect individual profile information for visitors across multiple sites and does not aggregate information from any other sources about browsing patterns of individual visitors across multiple sites.

**Principle 4 – Collection of Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

Vertical Leap Ltd collects anonymous visitor information such as the search engine used to visit a client site, the search query used and pages visited. Vertical Leap Ltd collects this non-personally identifiable information for the following purposes: (1) to provide anonymous statistical analysis visits via organic search engines to our customers for their web sites; (2) to administer our web site and servers, (3) to allow for auditing of our services by third parties, and (4) to improve our services.

**Principle 5 – Anonymous Use of Cookies**  
It is Vertical Leap’s policy to use cookies only for more accurate anonymous traffic analysis such as tracking the search engine used, the search query and the pages visited on a client’s website. The cookie information does not include personal data such as name, age, phone number, e-mail address or mailing address. In addition, Vertical Leap does not link cookies to personal data such as name, age, phone number, e-mail address or postal address. As we do not build a database of individual visitors, the data that we do collect is never stored in any individual user profile; the data collected serves only to update aggregate counts allowing our customers to monitor traffic on their site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to reject cookies.

Vertical Leap customers use customised JavaScript tracking code provided by Vertical Leap to track anonymous information about their web site visitors’ activity. This code contacts Vertical Leap’s servers, receives a response, and loads an image to the page. This 1×1 image is called a clear gif or web bug. This JavaScript tracking code does not collect personal information such as name, age, phone number, mailing address or credit card numbers from visitors to our customers’ web sites. Visitors may elect to opt out of receiving tracking cookies for all sites using Vertical Leap’s services. Please visit our opt-out page for more information.

**Principle 6 – No Individual Profiling**  
Vertical Leap Ltd does not create individual profiles of visitors. We do not have a database of individual profiles of each visitor. Vertical Leap collects data in aggregate form and data is not recorded or stored about individual visitors.

**Principle 7 – Third Party Access**  
Our customers control access to Vertical Leap Ltd’s analysis reports. Vertical Leap does not provide access to anyone other than the visitors identified by our customers.

**Principle 8 – Opting Out of Tracking Cookies**  
You may elect to opt out of receiving tracking cookies for all sites using Vertical Leap’s services. To do so, you will need to accept a cookie indicating your choice. Please visit our opt-out page for more information.

**For More Information**  
If you have any questions or comments about this policy, our services, or your experience with Vertical Leap, you can use the Feedback page on our site, or write to us at:

Vertical Leap Ltd  
Boathouse 6  
19 College Road  
Portsmouth Historic Dockyard  
Portsmouth, Hampshire  
PO1 3LJ  
England
